It's like my family. I definitely have no subjects.
Hey Daniel, hey Eric.
Welcome back.
Thanks so much. Yeah, it's great to be here.
Hi Virginia.
No.
All right, let's kick off.
I wanted to start out with some reminders.
First, we have a book club coming up on inspired in four weeks.
On August 7th, I just re-read it myself.
It's a good read.
It's highly aligned with how I think about product management and does a good job of explaining
why some of these things are important.
That I also believe to be important.
So it's nice to have another voice explaining all of that.
So please do read that.
I think I'm going to update the new hire on boarding dock and ask all new
hires to read this as well so that we all, everybody in the team is on the same page with
respect to this book.
Let's see.
Reminder B.
Remember there's this interview spreadsheet.
CS and sales have populated that with the number of customer
contacts for meetings.
Please do follow up on that.
I want to ensure goodwill with that team and follow up promptly with meetings with these
customers so that that team can see that we're taking advantage of it.
Third reminder, we've got a little engagement survey.
I'm going to run this once a month in Q3.
Just to take a pulse given all the change going on, please do take a minute to fill it out.
It's five.
Quick questions and then one free form where you can share whatever feedback you have.
Fabian didn't receive it.
I'm pretty sure I went through my emails.
I think I was some maybe it's on my end but I'm happy to fill it out.
But I didn't get it.
Need to get it to you.
All right, I will I'll ask Jessica to recent that to you.
Anybody else in the same condition where you did not receive it?
I don't recall but is there a way to put the link to the survey in the agenda?
Well, it's it's personal.
It's it's tied back to your user ID so we can track which team are on and that kind of thing.
I do believe it's anonymous but nevertheless everyone has their own customer ID.
So I'll ask Jessica to send it to Fabian and Karina.
Anybody else?
I just I hadn't seen it.
Scott, but I searched my email real quick and it looks like that's the title of the email.
So if you just searched for that in your your email, you should be able to find it if you got it.
Paul's survey.
Culture ramp.
Okay.
Anybody else didn't get it?
Please ping me.
All right.
Next reminder we we need we have a goal of at least three customer interviews per PM.
There's an okay R issue out there.
If you haven't updated it lately, please do so.
And remember we have three weeks until Q2 to hit our goals.
A please please do invest the time to get those set up and get at least three done if you haven't already.
Next one category maturity page last week.
We talked about this Josh did a great job of creating some new views.
One of which is sort of this flow chart showing how mature we're going to be at a given point in time,
which raised questions about whether we were forecasting that accurately.
If you haven't already, please go in and either confirm that it's accurate or update it.
Thanks to Kenny for creating that issue.
Somebody added direction maturity page.
No talk about that.
Well, I would just mean just a few ear offensive songs add in the link there.
That's also folks in the scene the updates there for the charts.
I just check it out.
So got it.
So it's a good way you can get a sense for like, you know.
It's hard when it's in tabular form, but when it's charted, it's much easier to see.
Like if it's achievable or not based on some of the trends.
And there's also fiscal down stays level trends as well.
So you can see higher stage in particular is trending or said to be trending.
So.
Great. Thanks, Josh.
All right, some team updates. We hired a couple more PMs. We got a good rhythm going on hiring.
We hired Gabe Weaver. He originally came through. They growth funnel.
But we have a really strong candidate for that fourth slot.
So we're going to target Gabe for third managed PM.
The chart or that team is to be defined. But bottom line. We're going to have a third group in the
managed area. And Gabe will lead that. And then dove, her skivets. We just hired him.
As the APM monitoring, he's got a great background in monitoring. And it's most recently been
elastic. So thank you to everyone who's been involved in the hiring loop. I know it's
taking a lot of energy from everybody. But I think our hiring processes continues to pick up speed.
Be to be worked with with Christy and David Sakamoto to change in language around customer
results. Just want to make sure you all saw that. So there's the MR.
It's got on that one. I just the there's a the diff highlights what is new content. I believe.
And there's one section that is great. I can totally understand why I would add that about prioritize
ruthlessly. But then the rest is I guess a bunch of formatting changes. And I don't know if there's
new content in any of the dog feeding. I guess the TLDR, the addition of that prioritize ruthlessly,
or is there some other point we were trying to make in this change?
It's been a little while. I think there were a number of changes. But before the handbook basically
read that internal feedback is worth 10 times more than external feedback. And I understand why we want
internal feedback because of dog fooding and using our own product. It's a it's a great channel
for feedback. But I think it was sending the message that customers weren't nearly as important
as internal opinion. And both Christy and I want to move off of that position. Like we should be
customer first and treat our own teams as a customer. But I don't want people to interpret that
our own internal opinion as worth 10 times more than a customer's opinion. If that makes sense.
So it is mostly language wherever that showed up in the handbook.
Catch it. Okay. The one comment I had on this is that some of the text seems like we should
focus on core competencies as opposed to new scope. And like as in the we should focus
for what we're about to add. So anyway that's one thought I had on this.
What? I don't remember that being the point of it. Maybe it reads that way. I don't know.
Feel free to continue to suggest tweaks. The point was let's prioritize and do what matters most first.
Just it's kind of what I've been preaching the whole time. Like let's in your area.
Wherever that is, do what matters first. Don't try to do it all. At once, we're going to have to
work our way through. That was the point. Yeah. I don't know if this is a follow-up issue.
And the way you described it, it doesn't seem controversial. But I will say there was a big
discussion and a recent initiative from Sid and other leaders that we should heavily prioritize
dog-fruiting because there were parts that are teams within the company that were not
utilizing our features. And we wanted to make sure that the product team was responsive to requests
from them. It's a little bit different than saying it's about our internal opinion. We should
we had always said we should validate it. That clarification is good that we want to make sure
it's about us saying this is in line with where we want to take the product and where we're
hearing customers. But if the internal customer wants it, we should, the original thinking was that
we should emphasize it. If the intent was to make sure we were just clarifying that same position.
But if we're saying, actually, we should pull back from the push for more dog-fruiting.
No. Maybe a different one. I would. Please don't conflate the two.
We very much still want a dog food. I think the point is when you're thinking of customers for
your thing, think of our internal teams early. You can get great feedback from them. They have an
incentive to work with you. There's very little risk in rolling out things early to them.
So treat them like a customer and think of our internal teams early as you're rolling something out.
That's still very much the message. But let's not over-rotate on internal feedback or internal
opinion. Let's still seek external feedback too because that's just one customer of many.
Cool. Okay. Okay. Okay. It does.
All right. Two C customer training, discovery training coming soon.
Sarah O'Donnell and her team are going to do a bunch of sort of quick videos on a variety of customer
discovery topics. So super excited for that. They should start dropping any day now. I think starting this week.
And so we'll release those two as they come out. We'll embed them in the how we work
description or team page as well. All right. Number three, 12, two. Kick off feedback. Josh,
thanks for leaving the charge. I thought you did a good job of MCing and sort of adding
color commentary in between. I thought the screenshots definitely helped.
There were a bunch that did not have them. I was wondering why is it just because we're not
there yet on many of these? Yeah. Okay. Yeah. I mean some of the commentary I don't know,
or Nicole added that. Yeah. Many of the issues we're saying we're going to do UX, front end and back
in the same iteration. So it hasn't started. And in some, I can think of a number of where
they're just aren't appropriate screenshots or at least there weren't screenshots or mockups
created in advance. Okay. For the purposes of front end working on it because front end was going
to work on it without a mockup. Okay. I love to get to where we're a bit ahead. So we'll have more
of these earlier and hopefully the customer discovery flow will get us further ahead on that.
In my case, some of the features also just have no UX component as a no UI component that could be
speech or it's understood. Yeah. I don't expect everyone. I mean, user judgment if it doesn't
need it fine. But where we do need design, it'd be great to get at least a month ahead. So
as we roll into dev, we have that to offer them. Scott, just a quick question to you. How do you
feel about presenting like balsamic or super low-fi mockups on the kickoff call? Find with that.
Okay. That could be an option too for PMs that are waiting for UX stuff. We're at the same
sprint. And I know that plans done a pretty good job at at least in the past of kind of running ahead
of UX and saying, okay, this is kind of what I think I want this look like before spinning UX
cycles on making a more high-fi mockup. So just that. If you think it does a better job
of describing it than the issue itself than use it. I think in some cases, a picture can be worth
a thousand words. I mean, I don't know how many words you throw at something. It's like,
for example, one of my things that I request or I I reported on for the release, the kickoff meeting
was expanding the epic view in the roadmap. And like those are basically just a bunch of buzzwords
put together that you're like, okay, what does that mean? Expand epic and I'm just, I literally
thought on that one for like 20 minutes saying, how do I make this epic? How do I make this issue
titled like more descriptive for customer value? And it just came down to like, that is the functionality
we're adding. What does that mean? Oh, here's the screenshot. You can see that we're going to add a
drop down and you can see the issues and the children uppicks that are attached to that epic. And in
that case, like I was like, I'm so thankful I have a screenshot. Even though that one is actually
not a high-fi mockup, it's more as more low-fi, it was a little bit pieced together. So,
yeah, I think like in general, there's a lot more value if we can show something like that.
So, you know, the product manager, you can you can consider that. You should feel free that you
you're empowered to take a tool that you're comfortable with, even it might even be just like
go with slides and make something that gets you at least out part of the way there in terms of what
you want to experience to look like. Yep, perfect.
3C, I thought the talk track shifted. I was definitely more a problem focused. I noticed a number
of speakers really trying to zero in on that, which is perfect. Some of them could have been more
problem focused, I thought. So, just keep considering that as you, as you, it's important to be
able to pitch these things in ways that people that aren't close to it can understand. And so,
just think about that. How do I explain this as someone who's cold, who doesn't know a darn thing
about this, why should they care? That getting that crystal in your thinking is going to be
important no matter what. So, it's time will spend. Thanks, Scott. This is Green Island. I just said
add to that if you don't mind. I think this has always been a challenge in product, even before I
joined GetLab for many people's how to get there on some of this terminology.
Those of us have deep technical background. So, my thought would be, is there a way that you can
start sharing or applauding good examples of this so that the product team can start to kind of
reminate on this and develop that scale if or not there yet? Yeah, I thought Lucas were very well
framed up. Those, those two popped out at me as yeah, that's the problem we're trying to solve.
Check those out. I'll all look through for some other examples.
Thank you for the suggestion. All right, 3D, we went long. We just have a ton of speakers,
which I love that lots of people get a chance to speak. So, I'm good with that, but we're going to have
we're going to have to limit the number of items probably. So, it looks like there's some other
ideas in here. Perhaps themes. Yeah, I mean, if there are some that relate to each other,
you could just tell a story. Hey, we're trying to prove this and then A, B, and C, tie back to it.
I think it's okay to be pretty brief in your description as long as you're hitting. What it is
and if somebody is really interested, they can dive deep. The themematic is a good idea.
The courted video, if you really want to go deep, maybe it's technically complex.
That's a great idea and then you can just cover the customer value to high level,
only the detail to the video. Watch statistics. I think Josh looked this up last time. I think
he said there were a thousand, oh, there we go. Kenny's putting it in. So, somewhere between
500 and a thousand. To kind of add to the time, just a feedback, I was timing myself this time.
And I had two features listed and I hit three minutes in 14 seconds. Obviously,
I was short in that. So, when we talk about, you know, I think somebody mentioned doing two or
coupling it down, it's interesting that I landed there with the two that I chose.
Yeah, that feels about average, but we've had how many speakers will probably have to be a
couple minutes max for person? I mean Eric pointed this out in the next line. I do think we
are due for a rethink of how we're doing the kickoff because we're going to have next month,
we're going to have 25 people trying to give content and even at two minutes already gone.
So, yeah, we expanded it. I will give a shout out for Jason, I know, because he's on
paternity leave created a video, but I think the original intent of the kickoff was actually just
as a company we had a retrospective and a kickoff. A retrospective immediately followed by a
kickoff and we just decided to post that on YouTube. I mean, I post a whole bunch of content on
YouTube. So, just having what you would normally do for your kind of like grooming or kickoff
within your individual group posted to YouTube and us, maybe having a specific channel for people
who wanted to follow it. We should discuss the issue and come up with something I do think prior to
next release kickoff. Just to evaluate alternatives to the format? Yeah, I mean, I don't even
if we said every person has one minute. I feel like we're doing a disservice because we're now
highlighting much less because we feel like we have a time constraint and need to keep it into one
synchronous 30 minute block. I need to do that. Okay. Yeah, plus one to the revamping it, I think
I think we're trying to, it's like, it's got so many jobs right now that we're not doing a good job
it any of, if we're one of them. I think that feels the most important customers are internal
and it's just like when it's getting internalling about because like, the people tend to think that
we had like 50 people on a Zoom call alone not even considering YouTube and people were asking
about what happened to YouTube link and things like that. So it's well attended internally
to think there's sort of alignment. So I'm going to let him know, you know, marketing value of like
that sort of like a release, for fictional customers it kind of feels like that, that are off
of them like a webinar or live stream on the release date. Right. Yeah, maybe the externally
focused one would be more about what we just shipped. There was a webinar that used to happen
called release writer. I think I participated in a couple of those three of them back to back
and they were pretty poorly attended from what my experience was and I think they actually got
ended by the product marketing team for that reason. I'm sure someone from that team could actually
give feedback. But I think one thing about the time limit is it's really hard to motivate
problems particularly like in a short amount of time particularly when they're very technical like
as product categories grow in maturity and sophistication like the problems become more and more
specific that we're solving and so motivating those specific reasons and why we're going up to like
this specific tiny piece of the very mature category. It's hard to do with 30 seconds
in a way then. So if we want to do that better that's going to put more and more pressure on
like communicating every reasonable number of items. I think. Okay. Thank you all for the feedback.
I like the idea of creating an issue and perhaps tweaking the format before next month. I also like
the idea of asking internal and external constituents with a like or don't like about the format.
Yeah. I just want to finalize that on that. I love that it's a half an hour. I almost even
like take particular categories over over a link thing the time as an example just because I
feel the feeling that if you want to watch it consistently it's going to be in that block. But that's
like if other customers are saying it would like the larger block then that's the right way to
go. So that's where I love to get feedback and some fashion to say okay you know here's how we
should change it. But we clearly have gone breath wise we've gone so much broader that it's going to
be hard to have all the topics in it. Okay. Thanks Kenny for starting the issue.
James, over to you for number four. Yeah. I just thought I'd share this for many I think many on this
call haven't heard not conspets speak about product discoveries but he advocated that this
quite a number of times previously from his experience reckoning these that a prior company.
So the idea is kind of different to it. I guess a UX discovery sprint I think Fabian linked one of
the books about that where it's really focused on UX iteration and research the product discovery
sprint is more focused on kind of like actually building something iterating on something that's
built and trying to get to some sort of NVC really quickly by trying to make the process more synchronous.
So the source code group is going to try and do that around file by file. Different navigation
to solve performance and usability problems in 12.3 and I thought it'd be interesting to
share that because internally we've been wrestling with like how to make this work well in an
async slash remote environment. So we're looking at trying to confine the participants in a specific
time zone so that we can all be available with the significant amount of overlap but that's also
difficult because we have it kind of excludes automatically 50% of the team who are just geographically
remote from any of their peers. We only have one UX designer that's only available in the
European times zone. So some interesting challenges there. If it goes well we're going to try and replicate
it a release or two later on a different problem that is also really complicated and hard and we're
going to make progress on quickly but I'll share any findings we have and if anyone's interested
discussing that we need more and put a meeting my calendar or drop me a set message. This is great
James. By the way I think the UX team is going to run well let me just say we have the option to
run one with Google Ventures who's one of our investors in that sprint book that Fabian Link 2
was written by a guy from GV they did hundreds of these things for our clients they know what they're
doing so if we get a chance to do one with them we should we're going to have to figure out how to
do it within our ASIC model though. So whatever you learn from yours James please feed that back
super interesting topic I think if we could get good at this ASIC honestly that would be a breakthrough.
Yeah I think one other interesting challenges that the sprint sort of terminology is kind of
challenging and like it's not sustainable to be doing design sprints or discovery sprints on a daily basis
whether or not we were in person or not it's not scalable to actually sprint all the time so
choosing the right task choosing the right time is I think one of the other challenges.
I agree yeah you don't want to do this for everything because well if you follow to the letter
it takes a whole week and you're totally dedicated to it which is amazing for focus sake
but you can't get anything else done so depending on how we structure this it would need to be done
for things that are really big unknowns where dedicating a huge big chunk of time like that is worth it
and not everything clears that bar. I think it's also most relevant for
for stages that are very interesting to be doing in the very beginning kind of like
that iron was like one of their biggest example for Google ventures when they always say like
solving clinical trials for the world is like a super complex problem so they just figure out
what is this a standard we can do so that we can start getting there and I think these are the
problems that that is a sprint is useful. We used it pretty successfully in my last company around
pricing of packaging stuff and ran a bunch of interviews with customers on that so
I've seen it work. All right okay Christopher number five. Yeah just want to
call out we've over the past month we've had a significant number of outages related to dot com
and that affect at least a one customer revenue with actual and because of that you know we've
had some focus from an exact leadership perspective so I encourage everybody to look at that
document and kind of look through it and particularly there's a couple of things from an engineering
perspective make it where one is as we started it infrastructure to development board where we're
going to start matching issues up and trying to make sure that that those get prioritized highly
where appropriate particularly for anything that you know affects performance around these issues
the other issue that I put in there was one around that's listed specifically which is around
the fact of prioritizing P performance availability work so one of the significant features of this
up to go recent outage last week was is that the register server apparently can't handle the
load anymore and we started digging into it we found a bunch of stuff that we hadn't checked
it like for instance that is an example rj unit test where basically going and getting cashed
and there was no limit on the number of unit tests that could actually be cash so we were getting these
like blocks of like several megabytes of data that had the basically be transferred around and
read us and that's really what's affecting its performance overall from our cashing service perspective
so consequently it's got I said that to you I hope that's okay. It feels like it was like
you need to help out when it hurts the effect of how do we best make sure that we get this kind of
systematically going and I just want to make sure that everybody was aware and just kind of
hoping for a discussion with any questions or any feedback or early feedback on it from that
perspective. I added some comments to it Christopher. Okay I haven't had a chance to look
up all just about that problem. Can I ask do we and maybe make this a question for you do we categorize
performance issues as bugs? We do have a performance label but they should be under under bugs.
Yeah this is an example where oftentimes the way we treat performances is a reactionary.
This is trying to think about it more in a proactive way so like as an example I'll give a
horrible example but when I worked at Amazon tags originally when Amazon was created tags were
they were expecting to label certain instances and it turns out that all customer started using
20 and 30 or 50 tags and they realized tags were being used to basically share environmental
information so the VMs could they could put the same drop of code on two different VMs and
they could behave differently based on the tag which was a total novel way for customers to use it
so then they had the basic glue on it that number of tags they could use because it wasn't
scaling with the system effectively. So this is kind of another example where like I think we
got to start thinking in terms of you know like when we create something new a new feature of
piece of functionality like what's the cost associated with that right because like it does cost
something internal and I'm not asking product managers to necessarily think in terms of the
exact bytes but I am concerned to think in terms of like you know what are the expectations around
it because like as an example if we went back and looked at J unit test or reporting you know if
we said unlimited that's you know that's a tough engineering call right particularly guess it's free right
for customers to do is a minor standing we also don't have a number of reposemirers we don't have a limit on that
and that that seems dangerous yeah so I guess I would comment you know I think the product team
is expected to prioritize all things and to understand them deeply whether they're a security issue or
performance concern I think what you're highlighting is in order to be proactive I don't know if the
product team would immediately know the impact of a proposed change but maybe that's not
too many for our infrastructure SRE stable counterparts to be involved in vetting and looking at
issues early in the pipeline to decide whether or not they would yeah or or let's say we're
implementing a feature like let's say we were implementing mirror from scratch like the first
question we should be asking is it's like how many mirrors is a customer expected to be able to support
and what I want to start charging for if they get above the certain limit and you know
and right now we don't and you could argue that scaling is just as much a reason for customers to
start paying us as as feature sets that's that's kind of the argument I would do thank you
because those things cost money like whether we like to admit it or not
yeah Chris I would have I would agree with you on what you're trying to sort of shape up and call out
here and the sense of you know going through pages for example performance of getting those
pageal is loaded is not great and I don't know if we set out originally to track some of those
performance things but I think that performance and into your point can I think performance
should be somewhere incorporated as we move forward and something we should be thinking about
for scalability across the board because it's just as important as bringing forth that really cool
thing to them is that that really cool thing works and people will stay there to use it
I think just as a cycle I think we have something the product and book that I
would like a couple days ago on performance something like fast applications are like always
you know like more usable and I think that's that's definitely important and I also think that
Githleb.com is massive I think we have four million users and for example for GEO I know that
only by actually interacting with the infrastructure we are getting feedback on some of the performance
bottlenecks that we are just not seeing otherwise so I and so I think that's actually also
really valuable and in that regard maybe also again you know dog fooding these things helps and
I think with the combination of CD we may hit a lot of those things that we're doing.
Yeah and the dog fooding thing on that front is a little confusing me I met with
Marin to talk about that and you know there's sort of this mentality of looking at dot com first
or leading the dot com for scalability and I just it's not really crisp to me where we're going
from making sure that we're you know how we approach me ensure that we in tech scalability for dot
com if we're starting the dot com or restarting somewhere else from a dot fooding perspective.
I'm pretty sure the handbook says that we're meant to well at least the guidelines used to be
that for new features they were meant to be available and get lab dot com and sell post at the same
time and that there used to be a production rate pretty checklist that I think the engineering team
was responsible for. I know that for when we want to go there was a production readiness process
that we had to go through and certainly we could easily we consider these things on the source
code front where readily considering scale like moving terabytes of data from the database and the
object storage and considering all these sorts of things performance is very much a feature and
should be considered that and I think particularly in categories where adoption is still growing
and early stages of maturity performance like understandably is less of a concern because there's
low usage so like solving scale at like any normal level doesn't make sense commercially
like necessarily when usage is small so there is a bit of a juggling act here because
we don't want to build a product for billions of users if there's only I don't know 20,000 users
experimenting with our newest feature so there's an iterative approach that is to be taken but I
would agree that particularly coming from a team that's digging out a lot of technical debt
and solving a lot of performance problems all the time we probably historically not been very good at
picking the right moment to pay off technical debt and address performance problems until they become
fires so yeah so to that point just real quick James and sorry Scott I think some things are
obvious like when we look at our progressive deliveries strategy I think that we like if you
look at something like feature flags or something like that's something that I think is going to be like
I wouldn't imagine that that's not going to be a key feature that we're going to bring forward
so I feel like that should be a give me on whether adoption has yet struck or not
but the second thing that is not clear to me like again when I was interviewing Mary and about dog
fooding is that I noticed that Mary and like we don't this isn't we weren't they didn't come to us first
and so this is not scalable or this is not usable for us internally and so it's like the
approach and process moving forward to dog food in the right spots is not cleared to me or
what the best practice has been or if anybody's you know crack that yeah I can give a concrete
example please I did a call with Mary and a few months back around confidential murder quests
so we knew that customers wanted to resolve them we knew that we wanted to do that and we're trying
to get rid of dev.gilab.org so I had a video call with him and a bunch of acin conversations with like
I've got these ideas for what a first iteration looks like and then we did a few calls and worked
through them and worked out which were the things that needed to happen and so we're shipping the
first iteration of that and 12.1 but we coordinated with them and spoke I spoke with Mary
and quite a lot to make sure whatever we were building was useful and we'd solved the security
problems that they had as well as our own ones so yeah I agree it needs to be proactive when
often a ship something's useful or that the infrastructure team is going to want to opt into
unless we've had a conversation with them in advance. All right it's I'm 30 seconds I had one
like the last time you point it it's sometimes really important for customers as well that
we're running it on getlab.com before they adopt it so one example is we built SSL TLS support
in getily but it's not turned on in getlab.com and so the customer that we built it for isn't using it
because they're waiting for our production team to turn it on because they want to see before
they turn it on for their enormous instance have we actually proven it at the world's largest
getlab instance scale so I think that's one important reason why we always need to make sure that
features are on and I'm getting used on getlab.com. Just kidding again my rip sorry I got a couple
things I think we'd definitely have a stronger definition I've done as part of our precious delivery
right and so part of something that's done is it needs to run at scale and get lab.com 6.3
and not below the cost model not below performance and if it does it's just going to be rewarded
frankly and that should be the bar for getting features across the line that doesn't mean for new
features that have low usage that obviously they're impacted quite small but they still it needs
to be within reason I totally agree that you don't want to overbuild on the first iteration for
planning for millions of users to have about to make any sense but yeah I think that's one aspect
I think their aspect is that I'm coming across run pricing and we can maybe have a fall up here
on like a havoc update but I think it's interesting that customer is well absorbed the cost
on self-managed of compute and so for them if they want to have a ridiculous number of
you know mirror just then you know and it's fine because they're paying for it so use cases on the
time and so maybe a way of thinking about this is to have some level of controls you can set if you
want to hear the instance of all those sort of I don't have some way to control that
and matter behavior for when we're covering the cost of those things but yeah
anyways thank you all great topic Christopher please pile on that issue with thoughts on how to
handle this like you're suggesting on definition of done Josh.
All right Karina, six and seven. Yes so I submitted an MR for the product template yesterday
and we're going through this process of getting more self-organized in the release
area and with our engineering and user design partners and one of the things that we
recognize and it's documented in the issue below in number seven is you know one our delivery
percentage is not been great what you heard me talk about but it's been a great ramp that we need
to self-organize around some method and what we found and sort of the last prioritization for
a release scope is that we have a lot of oversized issues and features that you know honestly
need a need a beat or release to go through user research maybe look at the code if they've
never seen the code you know reviewed that piece of code before or makes the recommendations on
the best way to solve so I put some thinking around you know that sort of you know that dual
track mindset dual truck agile kind of launching off of what user experiences recently updated
for dual track agile so feedback on that and then the second piece is that this experiment
running is leveraging semi dual track agile approach just to organize our conversation
how we open issues for areas that we need a discovery beat versus presenting an issue that is actually
ready for delivery one thing that was interesting Scott we were talking about you know just the
kickoff call and having some you know images and and more to share um that's definitely where I
think we'd like to be with release is getting ahead of that curve and really having
I'm some concrete understanding and prototypes of what we're trying to to present deliver
but when we looked at sort of kind of going through that process you know this is really for complex
things or heavy lifting because you know it is about a 20 to 30 day lead time to come in
release so just and so we have some targets to improve you know our hypothesis on leveraging this
you get follow it there if you haven't put but um it kind of tied together but I love
and put on the handsbook piece. Thank you Karina for creating these and sharing these I think
you're on the right track in parallel I've been working with like Christopher and Eric and Christy
to outline a high level description of our software development life cycle which will have two tracks
this is sort of competing content there or maybe or maybe they could be merged so thank you for
doing this I may slow roll it a little bit to make sure that we have one way of describing
the flow we'd like to go through but thank you very much for getting it kicked off.
Any questions for Karina? If not Joshua what are you?
Yeah just a few of the basic announcements you're showing through a ring the promise
label to playing priority general meaning is large in the same I love we shouldn't be promising
teachers and so this is just a way to flag it and that way it's where minor for PMS that this issue
had some importance left to make sure on dependencies and so just be aware of it so you
can cover to use it I did note in the label text that it should only be applied by product managers
and in particular the response will be a good answer for that section so it shouldn't be
going to apply by cam is anyone else awesome I like that terminology a lot better thank you Josh
all right five minutes of spare anything else if not have a great Tuesday at a yes