Hey there, I wanted to show you a new feature which is cash holdings in manual portfolios.
You can now add a theoretical cash value in your manual portfolio which is helpful to
more closely illustrate the balance of your manual portfolio.
This cash balance will be displayed and added to your all holdings and all portfolio balances
too.
So to add a cash balance, what we want to do is click on edit portfolio and then we'll
click at the bottom edit lots.
And at the bottom of this edit lots worksheet, there is a box to add cash balance in portfolio.
I'm going to go ahead and add a value and hit save.
And once I hit save, you can see that the cash value is at the bottom of my holdings
tab and it even calculates the weight of the cash in my portfolio too.
So the weight is updated as well as the overall balance of my portfolio to reflect the cash
that I entered.
And as I said, this balance will also be added to your all portfolios and all holdings pages.
So if we go to all holdings, we'll see all of our portfolios and the holdings on one
page.
If we scroll down to the bottom, we'll see cash and if we expand the row, we'll see
that there's cash in my income portfolio and my second portfolio and the corresponding
weights to each one of those cash balances with my overall weights of all my holdings.
I can also update the cash in my portfolio when I'm adding new tickers to my portfolio.
So if I also click on the add symbol button and I find a ticker and I hit next, I'll be
able to add in a number of shares, a date of purchase and a cost for the new ticker in
my portfolio, which I'll do.
And I can edit the cash balance on this modal as well and hit save and my cash balance will
be updated there as well.
So this is a new feature, which is cash holdings in manual portfolios that lets you add a theoretical
cash value to more closely illustrate the balance of your manual portfolios.
Thanks so much.